komoot.com 2017-11-06

# Privacy | Komoot

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy complements our Terms of Service and explains how we collect, store, use and disclose your personal information when you use komoot, a service provided by komoot GmbH ("komoot", "we" "our", "us") on our websites, mobile apps and all related sites, widgets, tools, API and other services as described in our Terms of Service.

In addition to this Privacy Policy we summarized which of the information in your account is private or public and how you can exchange with other users. See the summary.

 _By using komoot and in particular by registering a komoot account, you are consenting to the use of your personal information. Please take some time to read this Privacy Policy and make sure you are happy with our use of your personal information. If you have any questions or concerns, you can contact us at[help@komoot.de](mailto:help@komoot.de)._

### Our Principles

We are following clear principles to protect your data and privacy:

  * We are giving you full transparency regarding data protection and privacy. If you have any questions please contact us.
  * You have full control over the information you publish and share using komoot. Please also read also this summary about your account settings options.

### Information we collect

There is certain information that we collect automatically for statistical purposes as the result of your use of komoot. This information includes:

  * the type of device, browser and operating system you use
  * the IP address of the device from which you access komoot
  * the site that you visited immediately prior to visiting the website
  * any search terms that you may enter into forms
  * the pages that you visit and specific actions that you take

You don’t need to provide us with any other personal information in order to visit komoot. However, certain services do require registering a komoot account and, by doing so, you will provide us with personal information as described in our Terms of Service.

### How we use and disclose Your Personal Information

We will collect and use your personal information in order to fulfill the purpose of using komoot and under the provisions of the data protection law of the Federal Republic of Germany. We will not share your personal information with any third party, except the following circumstance:

  * To other users: Any information you provide publicly in your profile will be accessible by other users of komoot (also see our account settings summary).
  * As aggregated data: We may aggregate your personal data with similar data relating to other users in order to create statistical information. However, none of this information would include anything that could be used to identify you.
  * Connected platforms: If you choose to connect your komoot account with other apps or social networks such as Facebook, Google+ or Twitter or share content to these platforms. Komoot is not responsible for these other apps or networks, so please make sure you only connect your account and share content with apps or services that you trust.
  * Service Providers: We use certain third parties, some of whom may be located outside of the European Economic Area, to provide us with specialized services to improve our services for you. These third parties will have access to certain information about you, but only where this is necessary in order for those third parties to provide their services to us.
  * If required by law: If we are permitted or required to do so by law, including in response to a court order or other legal demand or request.

### Deleting Your Account

You can delete your account from your account page. If you delete your account, all personal data will be deleted and may not be recoverable. So back up all content uploaded to your account before you delete it. Statistical information and usage data might not be deleted but disconnected from your personal data. However, none of this information would include anything that could be used to identify you.

Please note that uninstalling our apps will not delete your komoot account.

### Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. These text files can be read by these websites and help to identify you when you return to a website.  
In common with most other websites, we use cookies and similar technologies to help us understand how people use our service so that we can keep improving komoot. You can block or disable komoot cookies using your browser settings. However, doing this could limit the service of komoot.

In addition to our own cookies, we work with various reputable companies to help us analyze how komoot is used, and to optimize our website and apps to deliver the best possible experience:

> ### Google Analytics
> 
> Google Analytics and Google Web Optimizer are services provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyze how users use our website and apps. The information generated by these cookies (including your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your and other users' use of komoot compiling reports for us on website activity and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. You can find more information[here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html), including a link to Google's Privacy Policy. 
> 
> To opt-out of analysis by Google Analytics on our website and other websites, please visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>
> 
> ### Social Plugins from Facebook, Google+ and Twitter
> 
> Our website uses social plug-ins ("plug-ins") provided by the social networks Facebook Inc. (“Facebook”), Google Inc. (“Google”) and Twitter Inc. (“Twitter”). The plug-ins are identifiable by a Facebook, Google or Twitter logo or a “like”, “+1” or “tweet” button. When you visit a page of our website that contains a social plug-in, your browser establishes a direct connection to the servers of Facebook, Twitter or Google. We have no impact on the amount of data that Facebook, Twitter or Google collects with the help of these plug-ins in particular when you are logged into Facebook, Twitter or Google+ and inform you according to our state of knowledge: Even if you are not a member of Facebook, Twitter or Google+ there is the possibility that they read your IP address and store it. If you are logged into your Facebook, Twitter or Google+ account they can assign your visit of komoot to your Facebook, Twitter or Google+ account. So please read also the privacy policies of Facebook (<http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>), Twitter (<https://twitter.com/privacy>) and Google (<http://www.google.de/policies/privacy/>) to find more information about purpose and scope of data collection.
> 
> It is also possible to block these plug-ins by using add-ons for your browser, for example with the "Facebook Blocker".

### Access to Your Data

Most of your personal information you provide to us can be accessed and updated in the account page. If you wish to access any other personal information about you, please contact us in written form.

### Security Notice

Komoot endeavors to safeguard user information to ensure that user account information is kept private. However, we cannot guarantee the security of user account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time.

### Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy, and when we do so, we will also revise the effective date set out below. Please be sure to check back here from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes to this Privacy Policy. If we make material changes in the way we use personal information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our service or sending you an email.

Last update: 12th July 2013
